JIANING LI



A BRIEF BIO

I am currently a 4th year Ph.D candidate at Peking University. My research interests include computer vision and deep learning. My recent works focus on pose estimation, self/semi-supervised learning and person reidentification. Morever, I am interested in some related fields in computer vision, *e.g.*, multimedia retrieval, instance segmentation, detection and some related fields.

EDUCATION

Peking University (PKU), Beijing, China

2017 - Present

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Applied Technology.

Advisor: Prof. Shiliang Zhang

Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), Wuhan, China

2013 - 2017

B.S. in School of Computer Science and Technology

₽ PUBLICATIONS

Journal:

- Pose-Guided Representation Learning for Person Re-Identification.
 Jianing Li, Shiliang Zhang, Qi Tian, Meng Wang, and Wen Gao.
 IEEE Trans. on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (PAMI, IF=17.9), 2019.
- Multi-Scale Temporal Cues Learning for Video Person Re-Identification.
 Jianing Li, Shiliang Zhang, and Tiejun Huang.
 IEEE Trans. on Image Processing (TIP, IF=9.3), 2020.

Conference:

- Joint Visual and Temporal Consistency for Unsupervised Domain Adaptive Person Re-Identification. **Jianing Li**, Shiliang Zhang. *ECCV*, 2020.
- Global-Local Temporal Representations For Video Person Re-Identification.
 Jianing Li, Shiliang Zhang, Jingdong Wang, Qi Tian, and Wen Gao. *ICCV*, 2019.
- Multi-scale 3D Convolution Network for Video Based Person Re-Identification.
 Jianing Li, Shiliang Zhang, and Tiejun Huang. AAAI(oral), 2019.
- Pose-driven Deep Convolutional Model for Person Re-identification.
 Chi Su*, Jianing Li*, Shiliang Zhang, and et al..(*equal contribution). ICCV, 2017.
- VP-ReID: Vehicle and Person Re-Identification System.
 Longhui Wei, Xiaobin Liu, Jianing Li, and Shiliang Zhang. ICMR, 2018

Under review:

• PolarPose: Single-stage Multi-person Pose Estimation in Polar Coordinates. **Jianing Li**, Shiliang Zhang. *ICCV*, 2021.

Google scholar citation: > 700.

SERVICES

- Reviewer of ICCV, CVPR, ECCV, AAAI, VCIP, etc.
- Reviewer of PAMI, TIP, TMM, T-CSVT, TOMM, IET computer vision, etc.
- Teaching assistant of *Data Structure and Algorithms*, Peking University.
- Teaching assistant of Multimedia Information Retrieval, Algorithms and Theories, Peking University.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Research on compact image features and hybrid index based massive image retrieval.. National Natural Science Foundation of China, 2016-2019.
- Large-scale Person Re-Identification. Cooperative projects with MSRA, 2018.
- Vehicle video content analysis and retrieval. Supported by Beijing's Natural Science Funds for Distinguished Young Scholar, 2018-2020.
- Content analysis and mining in ground air integration video for smart city. National Key R&D Program of China, 2020-2022.

PATENT

- Deep learning based algorithm for image person re-identification.
 CN patent, No. 2017107801790
- Multi-scale 3D convolution network based algorithm for video based person re-identification. CN patent, No. 2019100130826
- Pose-guided representation learning method for image person re-identification. CN patent, No. 2019106779835
- Global-local temporal representation learning method for video person re-identification. CN patent, No. 2019114226010
- Joint visual and temporal consistency cluster method for unsupervised person re-identification. CN patent, No. 2020107071022

SKILLS

- Programming Level: Familiar with C, C++, Cuda and Python *etc*. programming language, and Caffe, PyTorch and MXNET *etc*. deep learning framework.
- Research Field: My research interests include pose estimation, self-supervised/semi-supervised learning, instance segmentation, detection and some related fields.
- Language: Chinese, English, Japanese.

♥ Honors and Awards

| | 3.5 0004 |
|---|-----------|
| 2021 Huawei Scholarship | May. 2021 |
| 2020 National Scholarship | Dec. 2020 |
| 2020 Peking University Academic Innovation Award | Oct. 2020 |
| 2020 Peking University Merit Student Pacesetter | Oct. 2020 |
| 2020 President Scholarship | Jun. 2020 |
| 2019 Baidu Scholarship Global Top 40 | Oct. 2019 |
| 2019 Peking University Qingyun Shi Excellent Paper Award | Oct. 2019 |
| 2018 Peking University Academic Excellence Award | Oct. 2018 |
| 2017 2nd Prize in 4th China Graduate Contest on Smart City Technology and Creative Design | Aug. 2017 |